americangirl.com 2012-12-21

# American Girl - Privacy Policy

**This version of the American Girl Privacy Policy has been in effect since November 1, 2005.**

Use of this site signifies your acceptance of the terms and conditions.

American Girl, a member of the Mattel family of companies, is committed to protecting your online privacy when visiting this web site operated by American Girl. We do not collect and keep any personal information online from you unless you volunteer it, and you are 13 or older. We do not collect and keep personal information online from children under the age of 13 without their parent and/or legal guardian’s consent, except in limited circumstances authorized by law and described in this policy. Please review the information below to familiarize yourself with our policies on web site privacy, so that you and your family can take full advantage of our sites. Please remember that this site and the servers that make this site available are located in the U.S. By using this site you agree to the transfer, collection, processing and use of data by American Girl, its affiliates, subsidiaries and parent companies.

IF YOU ARE UNDER 18, PLEASE BE SURE TO READ THIS POLICY WITH YOUR PARENTS AND ASK QUESTIONS ABOUT THINGS YOU DO NOT UNDERSTAND. IF YOU ARE UNDER 13, YOU SHOULD GET YOUR PARENT’S PERMISSION BEFORE GIVING OUT ANY PERSONAL INFORMATION INCLUDING YOUR E-MAIL ADDRESS TO AMERICAN GIRL—OR TO ANYONE ELSE ON THE INTERNET.

**A SPECIAL NOTE FOR PARENTS AND LEGAL GUARDIANS** : American Girl adheres to the Children’s Online Privacy Protection Act of 1998 (COPPA) and the guidelines of the Children’s Advertising Review Unit (CARU) of the Council of Better Business Bureaus, Inc. in each of our web sites for children.

Parents, you can help by spending time online with your children and monitoring your children’s online use. Please help us protect your child’s privacy by instructing them never to provide personal information on this site or any other without your permission. Upon proper identification, parents may review the personal information we have collected about their child, request deletion, or refuse to allow further collection or use for marketing purposes. Click here to print a copy of our [Parental Review Access Form](http://store.americangirl.com/parental_review.pdf). Please note that purchasing products at our American Girl E-Store requires use of a valid credit card or other valid payment method accepted by American Girl, and confirmation that the visitor is over 18.

Return to Top

**Does American Girl Collect Any Personal Information About Me If I’m 13 or Older?**

American Girl doesn’t require anyone to share any personal information about themselves in order to enjoy any of our websites. That means you can visit our sites without any need to register with us. However, most of our sites contain special sections and privileges for members that register. We do not collect any personal information from you or your teenager unless it is voluntarily provided, for instance when signing a guest book, registering for contests, sweepstakes, community areas, downloads, or free demos, completing our online customer surveys or purchasing products. The personal information we ask for is usually first and last name, mailing address, phone number and an e-mail address. See below for how we use this information. Remember, only people who are 18 or older may purchase products from our online stores. In addition, only a parent or guardian can register children under age 13 to participate in enhanced subscription services or certain community features at our websites. We may obtain customer lists, demographic and other information from other sources. We may combine this information with information we collect online to better understand your needs, improve our site, products and services, and to better serve you.

The personal information we ask for online is usually first and last name, mailing address, phone number and an e-mail address. We do not collect any personal information from you online unless it is voluntarily provided, for instance when registering for contests, sweepstakes, promotions, downloads, or free demos, completing our online customer surveys, joining a club, creating a gift registry, or purchasing products. See Question 5 below for how we use this information. Remember, only people who are 18 or older may purchase products from our online stores.

We also collect information from you offline, for example, if you contact us to request a catalogue, participate in a promotion, like a sweepstakes or drawing, or purchase products at one of our American Girl stores. In addition, only a parent or guardian can register children under age 13 to participate in enhanced subscription services or community features at our websites. We may obtain customer lists, demographic and other information from other sources. We may combine this information with information we collect online to better understand your needs, improve our site, our products, and our services, and better serve you.

Return to Top

**What Ordering Information Does American Girl Collect in Our Online Stores?**

We offer opportunities to purchase products online in our e-stores. Customers must be over age 18 and must use a valid credit card or other valid payment method accepted by American Girl to purchase products online. Visitors under age 18 can use the Wish List function while browsing the e-store, but cannot make purchases. When a customer places an order or requests a catalogue online, we collect information associated with the requested transaction, such as the customer’s name, mailing address, products ordered, shipping addresses, and/or credit card information. We ask for this information so that we may fulfill the order or catalogue request. When a customer places an order online, we will send a confirming e-mail message to the e-mail address they provide when placing the order.

Customers have the option of registering certain information for future orders while completing their online order. For the customers who choose to register, we will capture their login name, password, name and mailing address, alternate ship-to addresses, and credit card information. Once customers have successfully entered the required information, an account will be created for them online. Customers can access their online account information through the “My Account” feature at our site. We also retain this information in our database. When registered online customers return to the site to place subsequent orders, they can identify themselves with login name and password. If a customer includes a child’s birth date and e-mail address, this information will be used to help us provide products and services that meet customer needs, improve customer service, and to understand you better.

If you request a catalogue, online or offline, or sign up to receive promotional e-mails, including as part of a sweepstakes or drawing entry, we will retain your information in our database. To find out how we share information, please see Question 6.

Return to Top

**Does American Girl Collect Any Personal Information About Anyone Under 13?**

A child can visit our sites or areas of our sites directed to children without ever registering or providing personally identifiable information. We offer our child visitors opportunities to tell us about their interests through surveys. We may ask a child to provide a first name, age, and state when submitting a response to one of our editorial departments in areas directed to children. This information is completely voluntary. When asked for a name, children may use “screen names” (not a real name) in order to protect their privacy. Before any responses are posted to our website, an editor reviews all the responses received and deletes any personally identifiable information. When we post a child’s e-mailed submission to one of these departments, we only use the child’s first name, age, and state. We obtain parental consent to use photographs of children or register children for an online club.

We do not collect personal information online from children under 13 without their parent’s consent except in special, limited circumstances.

American Girl might collect an e-mail address and first name (or screen name) from your child under 13 without your consent online, but only in the following special cases:

  * If a child under 13 sends a request to us, we keep their e-mail address long enough to respond to them. American Girl deletes this information from our system after we respond. If a child under 13 wants to send an e-card, we use the sender and recipient’s e-mail addresses only to send the card. Please be aware that although American Girl uses filters, we are unable to control the content of e-cards where visitors have the option of creating a message.
  * If we offer an e-mail newsletter or other activity which requires multiple online contact with the child, we will ask for the child’s e-mail address and first name, and also ask the child for a parent’s e-mail address so we can notify you and give you an opportunity to opt out. If you no longer wish your child to participate in an e-mail newsletter, simply follow the instructions in the newsletter to unsubscribe.
  * Occasionally, American Girl has special site activities or promotions, like sweepstakes or contests, which are open to children even if they are under 13. We do not ask for more information from your child than is necessary for your child to participate in the activity.

In the latter situation, we require your child to give us your e-mail address also, so that we can tell you that they have registered in a promotion or for a service. If we need more than an e-mail address and first name (or screen name) to enter your child in the promotion or offer the service, we will notify you, explain what information we need and why, and generally ask that you (not your child) provide it. For instance, we might ask you for your mailing address so that we can send to you, for your child, any prizes your child wins, or for your telephone number so that we can tell you when your child has won. Any information you or your child give us in the above special circumstances will be removed from our marketing database once the promotion, program or activity is concluded, and after any legally required period for keeping such information is complete.

Upon proper identification, parents may review the personal information we have collected online from their child, request deletion, or refuse to allow further collection or use by filling out a [Parental Review Access Form](http://store.americangirl.com/parental_review.pdf) and mailing it to the address on the form. However, if you ask us to delete your child’s information from our marketing database, we may have to ask your child not to participate in our activities.

Return to Top

**Does American Girl Use Cookies or Collect Other Information Automatically?**

American Girl receives and stores certain information automatically whenever you visit our site. Examples of information we collect and analyze include the Internet protocol (IP) address used to connect your computer to the Internet; computer and connection information such as browser type and version; the operating system and platform you use; and pages viewed and time spent on our site. This information helps us to optimize your experience at our site. We also use cookies and clear GIFs, sometimes known as pixel tags or web beacons. If you register or set up an account, the information we collect may be associated with your registration information.

A “cookie” is a small file that is saved on your computer’s hard drive which contains non-personal information. Our cookies help us improve your online experience, allow you to personalize your pages, enable us to customize our offerings, and help you to participate in some activities or events on the site. For instance, we use cookies to keep track of your progress in certain games. If you leave the site and then return, cookies may allow you to continue the game so that you do not have to start all over again. Cookies keep track of items in your shopping cart and wish list in our online store. Cookies help us determine how many people visit our sites, which of our web pages they use and how long they stay there. This information helps us evaluate which of our web features are successes and which need improvement. You can disable the use of cookies through your Internet browser (like Internet Explorer). Check your browser’s Help menu to find out how. However, if you disable cookies you may not be able to take advantage of some features of our website.

We also use other technology, called clear GIFs (sometimes called pixel tags or web beacons). On our web pages they allow us to count visitors viewing our pages, and in promotional e-mails they can tell us when an e-mail has been opened.

For administrative purposes, we also collect IP addresses, which is the automatic number assigned to your computer when you surf the web. Certain Internet Service Providers may assign the same IP address to many users. Your IP address and cookies are not connected to any personally identifiable or on-line contact information like a name and address unless you order or register at our site; however, if you register, all information we have about you will be associated with your customer file. 

At our adult areas, like our online store, American Girl may work with third party network advertisers who use cookies, pixels, or transparent GIF files to help us manage our online advertising. These GIF files enable them to recognize a unique cookie on your Web browser. The cookie may be placed at our website or another website who works with our third-party advertiser, and allows collection of information about your visits to our websites and to other websites that are part of the network. We also transmit certain information about your site visit to our third-party network advertiser. The information that we collect and share in this fashion is anonymous and not personally identifiable. It does not contain your name, address, telephone number, or email address. It does identify possible interests in certain categories of products and services based upon your online activities. This information may be used for the purpose of targeting advertisements on this and other sites based on those interests, and to learn which ads bring users to our websites. However, it may tell us what other sites you have visited that are associated with the network advertiser. Should you wish to opt out of behavior based advertisements, please follow the directions on the AdChoices icon within the advertisement or [click here](http://info.evidon.com/pub_info/641?v=1&nt=1&nw=true) to opt-out of third party networks. American Girl uses the Evidon assurance platform to comply with the cross-industry Self-Regulatory Program for Online Behavioral Advertising as managed by the Digital Advertising Alliance (DAA). As part of this service, American Girl's online advertisements and Web sites are sometimes delivered with icons that help consumers understand how their data is being used and provide choice options to consumers that want more control. Please remember that we do not control the privacy policies of any third party.

Return to Top

**What Does American Girl Do With the Information We Collect?**

We use all the information we collect to improve our site, understand our customers, improve our products and services, and better serve you. We use the personal information we collect for a variety of reasons. For instance, if you register in a drawing, sweepstakes or contest, we will use the registration information to notify winners, or if you purchase a product, we will use the information to fulfill the order. Adults who register for sweepstakes or contests, or who purchase products online, may be added to a list to receive our catalogue or other promotions by mail. Occasionally, we might also e-mail you to provide information on upcoming American Girl products, web site updates and promotions, or about the products or services of carefully selected third parties whose products and services may be of interest to you. You can elect not to receive this information when you register. If you want to stop receiving such updates and product information from American Girl at any time, you can access “My Account” online or call 1-800-360-1861 to speak with a Customer Service representative. Our mailings and e-mails will also include information allowing you to ask not to receive such information in the future.

Adult visitors may be asked if they wish to provide additional optional information about family and friends who may be interested in American Girl products and services. This information will be used to send those individuals an American Girl catalogue (if they are not already receiving one) and offer them an opportunity to receive special promotions by mail.

See Question 7 below for information on the circumstances under which American Girl might share your information with a third party.

Return to Top

**How Does American Girl Safeguard Personal Information?**

The security of your personal information is important to us. We use Secure Sockets Layer (SSL) technology to protect credit card data during transmission to our website, and adopt careful internal procedures to safeguard personal information in our system. We also review our security procedures periodically to consider whether new physical, administrative or technical measures are needed. Remember, however, that despite our commitment to data security, we cannot guarantee that our systems or the Internet will always be secure. When you create a password and log-in name, we recommend that you adopt a unique name, combining letters and numbers that will be difficult for others to duplicate or guess. It is important for you to protect against unauthorized access to your password and to your computer. Be sure to sign off when finished, especially when using a shared computer.

Return to Top

**Does American Girl Share Information About Me With Others?**

American Girl does share names and mailing addresses with other companies outside the Mattel family of companies. American Girl will not share your e-mail address with companies outside the Mattel family of companies for their direct marketing purposes unless you have given your prior consent. Except as described in this policy, we never share personal information that we receive online from children under 13 with other companies. 

American Girl may give other companies access to our information database, but only if necessary to allow them to provide database or server maintenance or security, help us process and fulfill orders or requests, or provide other similar services to American Girl. If we do provide access, we require those other companies to sign confidentiality agreements promising to keep secret any information they see. All information may be transferred as part of the purchase or sale of a business.

If American Girl believes that anyone’s behavior on our sites may damage us or our sites or anyone else, we may disclose the relevant personal information in order to prevent this harm without notifying you or obtaining your consent. In that case, we might try to identify the wrongdoer, contact them or bring legal action against them. We may also disclose personal information if we reasonably believe that the disclosure is required by law, or in response to a legal request.

Return to Top

**How Can I Update My Preferences on Use and Sharing of My Personal Information?**

To update your contact information, change your mail or e-mail preferences on how we contact you, or instruct us not to share your mailing information with a third party, you can access “My Account” online if you have an online account with us, or call 1-800-360-1861 to speak with a Customer Service representative. Please remember that it may take time for all of our systems to be updated. To opt-out of receiving promotional e-mails from American Girl at any time, follow the instructions in the e-mail.

Return to Top

**Your Privacy Rights**

As is customary with many companies, we may share your name and mailing address with carefully selected companies whose products and services may be of interest to you for their direct marketing purposes. You can opt out at any time. If you would like to find out more about these companies, or request that we not share your information for direct marketing purposes, please e-mail us at [service@americangirl.com](mailto:service@americangirl.com), or complete the [Marketing Disclosure Form](http://store.americangirl.com/marketing_disclosure.pdf) and mail it to us at the address below.

Return to Top

**And Finally...**

We want you and your family to have fun online and urge you and your family to follow common sense whenever disclosing personal information - on this site or anywhere on the Internet.

Thank you for reading our privacy statement. We are genuinely committed to safeguarding privacy for both you and your children. We hope you have a better understanding of the many activities we offer and how we use information to improve our site, our products and services, and to understand your needs. Remember, we may change our policy from time to time. When this happens, we will notify you of the new policy by posting it on our site.

If you have concerns about your child’s use of our service, please contact us using our [feedback form](http://store.americangirl.com/pls/ag/pc_qc.comment_page). You and your child’s use of this site is also governed by our [Terms and Conditions](http://store.americangirl.com/pls/ag/icm_terms) statement. Please read it.

    	American Girl
    	
    	8400 Fairway Place
    	
    	Middleton, WI 53562
    	
    	608-836-4848
    	
    	e-mail: [im_cs@americangirl.com](mailto:im_cs@americangirl.com)

Return to Top
